um the final is tonight we have 18
divers and 12 of them will make it
through to tonight's showpiece final
well it only seems like yesterday we
were here in fact it was it was last
night
qualification finished well after 10
o'clock UK time now it's just before 10
a.m.
and 18 of last night's 32 divers back
here and ready to compete again taking
the traveling time to and from the
athletes village these divers like Tom
Daley here will be lucky to have got 6
or 7 hours sleep the British diver
getting a massive round of applause from
another impressive crowd here Tom Daley
was one of the divers who have an
inconsistent evening in qualification
Steve ravillious alongside me yet again
often sleep cheering for the local hero
dies down and Steve how surprise to you
at this schedule they're back here so
quickly aren't they they are and I just
worry that it doesn't allow the athletes
to give of their best because as you
point out we finished here about 10 20
10 15 last night they may have got back
to the village by 11 they may have
needed a massage something to eat if
they got to sleep by midnight I'd be
very surprised and then they're going to
be up by 6:00 6:30 and operating on six
hours sleep it's just not ideal so the
scheduling is curious at best and it was
a very long session last night that they
had and in fact during that there would
have been maybe a couple of these guys
required to do a drug test which would
have held them back even further so the
scheduling has raised a few eyebrows but
I think that said we're in for a great
competition if last night's is anything
to go by and the two Chinese boys are
going to be very difficult to to remove
from top spot linear and Chabot were
absolutely outstanding with their skill
level and their consistency across the
six stars yes the dive order today is
seeded from yesterday's qualification
process still get the feeling it doesn't
really reflect the true talent that's
out there in the diving pool the
Mexicans and the Germans had excellent
evenings like Martin Fortran who got
themselves in good positions and can
watch the dives unfold last night's
competition with 32 divers took more
than three hours to compete so there was
half an hour wait between each die for
each diver and interesting to read some
of the overnight quotes from the divers
saying how difficult they found it and
didn't know quite how to handle it
Matthew Mitchum said a really
experienced diver like like himself Tom
Daley who has very inconsistent said
that his legs felt tired at the end and
I've got a feeling we really haven't
seen the real competition emerge
apart from as you said those two Chinese
superstars at the top of the order
another indication that for some at
least it was a long night three of the
top six divers their last dive was their
worst and then look at someone like glib
galperin who just staggered across the
line in the end but he's ranking across
the night he started second then second
after the second dive then fifth fifth
15th and 16th and he only just made it
so there you see glib galperin the
Russian going off third which means he
was third last to qualify and this was a
surprising performance but indicative of
the inconsistency we saw well last night
many of these chopped dry divers who can
pull out a top scoring performance with
one single effort had a little bit of
slack in their program they could afford
maybe to dip their standards a little
bit but now we're getting to this
semi-final stage and even more so
tonight a mistake a poor dive will be
really costly I really think we're going
to see the whole level crank up here
this morning and certainly the pressure
will increase those laps is not going to
be allowed it was a long line for the
judges to who have to assess these dives
so have one look at it they don't get
the advantage of the excellent TV
replays which we can all enjoy seven
judges the top two and the bottom two
marks are discounted it's very clear
when you see the score captions come up
at the end of each dive and
the only ones who really manage that
terrific consistency were lin dawei here
and chuubo his chinese compatriot they
were incredible the big feature of these
Chinese diverts is they never seem to
let their standard drop excellent is
slight their bottom line now David
Boudia silver medalist at the World
Championships last year again someone
who had an inconsistent night he's come
in in the last place and so we'll go off
first and all the divers that have made
the semi-final are doing the same six
dives as they did in the qualifying the
preliminary we're gonna go look at Tom
Daley there he is the Great Britain
poster boy one of the faces of the
build-up to these London 2012 Olympic
Games been under tremendous pressure of
expectation and this crowd so many of
them who will probably be new to this
sport but they know it's spectacular and
they will be willing daily along after a
difficult evening for him but he's by no
means the only star of the show for you
to enjoy not far from a start then David
Boudia will lead us off with an arm
stand back double somersault two and a
half twists and different strategies
about where you put your high tariffs
dives start off with one which is going
to be the case for David just a reminder
every dive has a degree of difficulty or
a tariff it's three point six this and
that figure is multiplied by the sum of
the three middle scores they get now the
diving pool can settle down and await
the start of competition we David Boudia
from the United States twenty-three year
old from Abilene in Texas getting us
under way with an arm stand back double
somersault two and a half twists which
is a strong opening dive
solid start from him and this was one of
his better dives last night at hauled in
81 points and with the higher tariffs
dives decent execution is going to get
you a healthy score and start as you
intend to finish well this is very
promising for David minimal splash good
angle of entry and an 88 point - so
straight off he's improved on his
beginning from last night next up is
Jose equator of Cuba forward three and a
half somersault hiked for weather who
like quite a few of these divers also
competed in the 10 metre synchro event
where he finished in fifth position much
lower tariffs on this dive which he's
executed well he's going to get eight
and eight in the house but he won't
score as highly as David Boudia somewhat
mucked up his first dive last night it
was this one the only had 58.5 so 76.5
well there's an improvement as well and
a significant one by some 18 points
that's huge so he's on his way
momentum and confidence so important to
these divers through the competition now
this is glib galperin who had a storming
start he's 27 years of age very
experienced but had a horrendous amount
of injury and again he started well he's
controlled that entry beautifully and
just flattened the water pulled the air
down with him and he opened with an 88
yesterday and he's the one who has to
deal with the upcoming up applause and
performance of Tom Daley but eight and a
half's across the board pretty much from
the judges and an 81 point six
[Applause]
right for the moment the crowd realized
that next up is Tom Daley control degree
of bedlam breaks out I think that
reflects the anxiety everybody feels for
this young teenaged superstar second
Olympics competing when he was just 14
in Beijing my camera angle that is Tom
Daley back two and a half somersault two
and a half twist well it was a good
entry buddy on our angle we could see
that he wasn't quite square to the side
of the pool and that leg angle may well
have been caught by the judges very
difficult with this amount of twisting
to line yourself up properly and he has
been marked down a little for that he
opened with a seventy three point eight
yesterday
so it's just slightly twisted to the
angle he desired and an 81 though so he
too has found some improvement when it
matters
PA announcer asking the very
enthusiastic crowd here to refrain from
taking flash photographs not wanting to
distract the divers at all Victor mini
buyer from Russia opening divers in him
with three and a half somersault tucked
just 3.2 the tariff here
long hold at the top here
well he does a good job in the end we
always get to a little concern when they
spend that much time at the top that's
we've discussed it's like not being able
to put the powder on the ball in golf
it's almost the yips but it's a slightly
dangerous dive as they come in closer
with their head as you can see but he
had more margin for error than perhaps
that camera angle suggested only sevens
yesterday for that dive so he - so this
is a great start to the competition
Roger they're all lifting their
performance
it's Victor's first Olympic Games he's a
European silver medalist on the platform
moving on now to Victor Ortega or their
back to the half somersault one and a
half twists twenty-four-year-old from
Colombia and there is the first sort of
significant error on entry coming from
Victor or Tiger 75.2 for this opening
dive yesterday
but it'll be a lower return today a
slightly messy entry all good to this
point and then just miss times the
kick-out and the feet were slightly
apart of sight on the judges aren't
going to see that so much but sixty
eight point eight so he's given up about
seven marks on that opening diaphragm
yesterday ukraine's anton zakharov 26
years of age has been competing at the
highest level for more than a decade
first World Championships worth back in
2001 inward through the half somersault
tucked that was beautifully done and you
just caught a hint of that gas with the
crowd doesn't like to see their head and
body go that class at the end of the
platform but uh Anton knew what he was
doing well that is close this is going
to be higher than yesterday and a 72 for
his first dive how close that close I
don't know 20 centimeters a lot of good
height up off that platform to give
himself the the room and time to get
through the somersaults before he can
straighten out to make the perfect to
entry or it's near perfect if he can
make it seventy six point eight healthy
start as we move on to Riley McCormack
the Canadian who's 21 later this month
for with three and a half somersault
height to get off underway well it was
all right he had a little bit too much
forward momentum out into the pool to
create the vertical entry but there's a
lot of some ourselves to get through
here took it very close to the platform
before throwing himself out into the
into the ether there 72 to see him get
more than that he a number of these
competitors who have made the last 18
did not start well McCormick was won and
agreed it was another ranked leg wheeler
from Cuba forward three-and-a-half
somersault to open he got to the
semi-final in Beijing four years ago so
his ambition at least will be to go one
step further and make the top 12 after
the small wings competition better first
dive it's only got a low tariff of 3
yesterday only 61 and a half we had an
interesting angle for himself they're
coming from that side of the platform 72
big cheer goes up for the defending
Olympic champion who had a patchy night
Matthew Mitchum from Australia of the
big names of the platform we never knew
quite what to expect from mr. Mitchum
Eminem last night but he's got the big
one in his lock always capable of
pulling out something spectacular if his
somewhat injured body allows it he
admits that he can't put in as much
difficulty as he would like because he's
got some limitations now his dive itself
just tariffs of three he's all good
scores for it and there's opening 75
just under what he did last night update
there on the standings to date but it's
a little bit misleading because the top
guys are still to go towards the end of
the round
Nick McCrory from the United States 21
year old he got a bronze in the synchro
in with three and a half somersault
nicely finished well through and
somersaults to spot the water get the
entry just right
into a tight tuck knees up to the
shoulders and control the entry pretty
well see better ripped entries than this
straight eighths to count their seventy
six point eight zero alexander bond are
now from ukraine another one of the
impressive number of teenagers in this
competition just eighteen in would three
and a half somersault tucked
Oh excellent starts he had five very
good dives last night and one terrible
one his third to keep an eye on that one
is caught under 60 but he's commenced
well again here all the power going
through the toes on the end of the
platform and quickly through the
somersaults to give him plenty of time
to find a good entry you can have a
great synchro competition finished
eighth with solid sander gawrsh covers
off after finishing third in the timmy
de synchro in last year's World
Championship so he's got a little bit
more to come out still now the Mexican
divers are having a good games and a
good competition at 10 meters as well
this is even Garcia forward four and a
half somersault with a three point seven
difficulty and ambitious opening it's
done a nice job of it we're into the top
six now and we've got two competitors
from three nations Mexico Mexico in
Germany Germany and then the top seeded
two Chinese
not to get through here and that's a
great position he finds his he enters
and keeps the splash to a minimum so
he's gone very respectable scores there
in an eighty eight point eight to open
with Garcia has a silver medal from the
ten metre synchro with his countryman
German Sanchez who's now on the board
for a back three-and-a-half somersault
so these two divers have already
performed impressively and are still
going strong this was the top scoring
dive in the first round last night
or what it might well be again an 89.1
last night for German Sanchez with nines
across the board he has absolutely
controlled this he's in the flyweight
division seven stones six pounds that's
forty seven kilos his body weight which
is extremely light judge is not feeling
quite as generous as in the prelims and
an eighty five point eight as opposed to
he's eighty nine from last night but
pretty close as the standard rises in
this competition inevitably the counties
will be a little bit more push to be a
little bit more stingy with their
marking like that they really gonna have
to work for it but we've not been
dazzled by tens
I'm sure that's still to come possibly
tonight when their competition really
hots up Martin Wolfram now who's had a
very good competition to date I'm stand
back double somersault two and a half
twists a pretty good effort he's the
12th ranked dive in the first round last
night seventy seven point four observed
as we did that the splash was a bit more
than he would have liked maybe just a
little bit short of vertical on entry
and the ninety one point eight though
well judges did like it
lifting the top spot for the moment very
early days his countrymen Sascha Klein
dives next 26 year old in with three and
a half somersault tucked 3.2 the tariff
silver medalist in Beijing and the 10
metre synchro again nice and tied into
the end of the platform there's not
plenty of experience I think compared to
his country one fall from who's only 20
and experience is gonna count
increasingly as they go through these
rounds trying to keep that consistency
seventy six point eight about five marks
on his opening dive from the prelims and
now top two men class apart really Lin
you a 21 year old from Guangdong in with
three and a half somersault solid he
will improve is his second dive that
brought him and done last night let me
sand down he finished second but it
would he ended up with the 17th ranked
diver in the second series he had
several nines with his opening dive
yesterday but not quite so high here and
an 81 6
now the man who's been setting the
standards chuubo nineteen years of age
the favorite for the gold in wood three
and a half somersault tucked
well he was there so early he gets
through the somersaults in the blink of
an eye and he seems to have so much time
to get the entry right which of course
he's done this is his lowest tariff dive
and it was his lowest scoring dive last
night it just says he doesn't even
particularly like this dive but he's
kidding 9 to 9 and a half he must be the
only person in the pool that doesn't
like it everybody else could only admire
it and absolutely impassive through
competition isn't he eighty nine point
six he's found an extra three marks
there and that completes the first
series 12 the cutoff point remember
Martin for France
it's his first Olympic Games it's really
untested at this level and he's
performing superbly chuubo Ivan Garcia
Mexican boys will place their third and
fifth Sascha Klein more to come from him
and three divers they're linked on 11th
if they were level on points at the end
of six dives then they would all go
through there's no count back I think
I've added diving that they they would
share qualification and if it comes to
tonight the chair of medal as well just
a little surprising to see Sasha climb
down the list there he was never out of
the top five in the prelim David Boudia
I'm studying communications at Purdue
University Western Lafayette in Indiana
second dive in with three-and-a-half
somersault
nicely handled again from David this
wasn't one of his better dives last
night
mr. yielding seventy three point six all
but the judges like what they've seen
here they're very impressive entry and
very quickly through his somersaults
nice leg form and an eighty six point
four he's come to compete now he was a
bit rusty last night so we knew that
18th was no reflection of David's
potential who's a dweller from Cuba now
back three and a half Sava salt and
again massively improved on last night
well that died for him last night was
nothing short of a disaster he got
twenty one point six it was barely a
dive at all it's crashed into the water
well short and you'll be relieved to
have got it out of the way and with the
eights being announced he's the senior
Pro on duty today he's 33 years of age
the oldest competitor in the pool today
so 88.2 compared to twenty one point six
and that is a massive improvement and
maybe he is heading for the final will
be glib Cowper ins aim had eight
operations on back and knee problems and
missed a couple of years through injury
this is an arm stand reverse triple
somersault
or dear well short and that was a dive
that got in ninety 1.8 in the prelims
never looked in control really the arm
stander and the legs far from vertical
left so that's a potentially eliminating
him 37.4 depends what the others do and
if he can now a few big dives but now
Tom Daley
he was Britain's youngest team member at
just 14 years of age four years ago in
Beijing he's had some four years to
contend with since in with three and a
half somersault tucked for the 18 year
old
that's a super entry and the crowd
recognizes that and they're going to
work on the judges now to get their man
a big score fantastic reception every
mum in that crowd wishes their daughter
would bring Tom home for tea and it's
just got that sort of look he does and
he's absolutely mastered this dive
keeping it in tight to the end of the
platform he was operating on minimal
sleep he wanted to be here early getting
lots of practice before this session he
was quite disappointed in himself and in
86.4 he's found another eight marks on
that dive alone Victor mini bive from
Russia forward four and a half
somersault three point seven the tariff
here and you can expect victor to attack
this dive all the way one of the quite
physical Eastern European more powerful
looking divers good job
it was his top scoring guide last night
he wants it in the 80s again eighty six
point nine five that's what it brought
him at the first attempt just slightly
past the vertical
couple of eights and seven and a half's
in there eighty six nine five that's
exactly what he had last night
there you go you talk about consistency
victor ortega from colombia now straight
into his forward three and a half
somersault some of them really as soon
as they get the call they want to go
don't they
this is a bit disappointing for a tiger
it's a low tariff dive his lowest in
fact 3.0
and he's not done such a great job in a
lovely pike position just rolled the
feet over and created a big splash but
nose to knees very flexible beautiful
position through the air just didn't
quite finish it off and the sixty three
only well the low tariff hurts that dive
and on zakharov from ukraine World
Championships silver and bronze in the
past at the synchro events back three
and a half somersault now
very good look it he wasn't quite
vertical but somehow he controlled the
entry and the better divers can do this
you think they're in trouble when they
hit the water but they pull the air down
with them
and it minimizes the splash his angle
was slightly off too but I only catch
that on the second look Roger this is
the judges just don't see everything
it's too quick he's got an 86 point for
nearly as good as last night's 88 - when
the hands come together as they prepare
for entry into the water they're not
just punching a hole through the water
they're punching a hole through the air
as well they're traveling at such speed
Raleigh McCormick now from Canada back
two and a half somersault two and a half
twist three point six the degree of
difficulty here sitting 11th
done a nice job they he looked a little
twitchy on the platform I wonder how
many little flexors of there of the
ankles they were going to be until he
went it got good power off the platform
his feet a little loose reasonable entry
and you should get a reasonable score
but you see the ankles drifting apart
there the judges don't want to see that
and you don't want them to see it if
you're on the driver but in 86 for but I
think they saw much of it a couple of
forum problems there but we can just
stress again that the judges just don't
catch what we can see on the slo-moes
they get one look Claire a grader from
Cuba down in 16th now has an inward
three and a half somersault tucked to
try to improve that oh my goodness he
was tied to the end of the platform that
gasp from the crowd as they worry about
contact this was his top scoring dive
last night he got nines a couple of nine
and a half's in fact well that's too
close for me
and these solid concrete up there not a
bad idea to have that towel there that
would at least help with the if there
was any contact but there's a disturbing
range here I don't like seeing six up to
eight
that's great despair that just tells you
that one judge saw something that others
didn't or thought they did after you
Mitch him now
Brisbane born lives in Sydney studying
language and science at Sydney
University back at three and a half
somersault for one of the big names in
diving oh that's an entry he looks in a
little better form he's it doesn't look
like a gold medalist but he's he's got
something going better than last night
well he's done again a good job with an
entry that wasn't vertical and an eighty
five point eight Matthew
trying to become only the fifth man to
retain ten meter Olympic title there'll
be a quiz question on the other four as
the competition unfolds I've got a piece
of paper here that tells me so we can we
could both look clever that's right Nick
McCrory now from the United States arm
stand back double somersault one and a
half twist
he's also links there in 11th place long
hold again he met him stared all right
there wasn't a lot of power off the
platform from the arm stand it was more
out into the pool and up but that was
how he executed the dive last night when
he left the platform the arms are pretty
straight but a lot of power coming here
at this moment some of that's generated
by their legs of course as they flick
out good position on entry judge looks
sorry coach looks satisfied if not
thrilled in eighty three point two
fractionally better than his first
attempt last night alexander banda from
the u quaint a crane 18 years of age
forward four and a half somersault three
point seven
a little messy at the finish you know
four and a half somersaults good tariffs
offered here 3.7 but getting it just
right that's what the divers have found
difficult with this one he was competing
at European Junior Championship level
just last year so it is a massive step
up for an 18 year old to suddenly find
himself diving against the absolute
cream 77 seven he's given up about six
points on the same dive last night first
of the two Mexican divers Evan Garcia
he's 18 years of age the younger of the
two back three and a half somersault
this was his best dive last night tucked
position
oh that's great you know the analogy
with the gymnastics for that kind of
dive is it's like a blind landing
because you're reaching back searching
for the water they spot the ceiling a
couple of times three times kick out get
themselves vertical that's what the
trainings all about being able to do
that these back somersaults now he kicks
out now he finds the vertical that's
really well done and an eighty seven
four five well done judges really like
that now it's his synchro silver metal
teammate German Sanchez his forward two
and a half somersault three twists the
piked position piked the legs are out
straighten the clutching around the back
of the knees are tucked when they're
curled up into a little ball
a lot to get through there was their
eyes and he got through it all but
compromising the entry I think seeing
how vertical he gets here and just
flipped the he was a little bend at the
hips in the end barely timing that for
the panic position to actually get into
it he's almost out of it as soon as he's
into it ninety one point two though that
decent tariff of three point eight
Martin Wolfram competing at the highest
level of his short career and responding
to the challenge leading after the first
round in with three and a half
somersaults well he didn't really get on
top of this dive last night and got a 72
for it it's his lowest terror of three
point two so if he can get more than 72
always going to the judges love this one
well his entry is near-perfect a more
straightforward dive you really do want
to be making the most of the entry and
that Martin's done that with an eighty
six point four and a low tariff dive
that's an excellent return very
impressive Olympic debut Sascha Klein
his older more experienced countrymen
eight gold and two silver at European
level forward for a half somersault
[Applause]
he's got some support here well they
both have Sasha Cline and Martin Wolfram
and why not this one team 88.8 last
night might be a very similar score high
eighties perhaps for Sasha well ninety
point six five even better it's a so
impressed Roger to see so many divers
just finding you know another three five
ten points then you a needs to do that
this was six after the first dive
reversed three-and-a-half somersault
there he's a man with high expectations
is his first time he's competed at the
very highest level in in an individual
event normally it's been synchro success
this was the dive that troubled him last
night
seventy four point two five last night
with seven and a half's but much better
effort here totally in control from the
moment he left the platform that is a
very small splash from ten meters and a
ninety four oh five three nine and a
half's count only one night I don't
think we've seen so many nine-halves in
a set of figures so far cube Oh a world
champion number one favorite for this
the 19 year old from Sichuan with a arm
stand back triple somersault worth 3.5
oh well there is a rare identifiable
mistake from chuubo this was a dive got
him 99.75 last night but he's a little
bit initially in the pike and short on
entry so he is human
yes he was in Rome in 2009 in the World
Championships it came down to the last
three dives with himself from Matthew
Mitchum and Tom Daley and chuubo didn't
produce the dive on the day and nor did
Matthew Mitchum and that was when Tom
Daley stole the title so maybe at just
that little seed of doubt knows that
he's very aware that things can go wrong
but Martin Wolfram is really storming in
this semi-final it is just the
semi-final the Mexicans again in those
two Chinese divers in fourth and fifth
that's not their sort of natural dye
being habitat Tom Daley night Fair
Sascha Klein has dropped a little bit
David Boudia now starting to emerge in
12th Matthew Mitchum is where the cutoff
is but he's only 0.8 ahead of Nick
McCrory Rowley McCormick so there's
plenty more that can happen and gleb
galperin down at the bottom they're
holding up the rest at the moment for
the two Chinese divers just being given
something to think about
and satisfy themselves in the knowledge
that the scores don't carry forward to
the phone I just have to make the 12 and
then start again start afresh and
through one or two dives that didn't
please you you have to worry about them
there is that advantage perhaps if you
do dive last you do know at least what
you've got to do you also know of course
that there's nobody else who can make a
mistake so it is all down to you David
Boudia kicks us off having a much much
better series of dives so far this
forward four and a half somersault
tucked is worth three point seven very
tidy he's top scoring dive in the
prelims with an eighty eight point eight
it's a bit of a rush to reach the
vertical with this dive because there's
so many somersaults to get through just
powers off the end of the platform
in fact he almost over rotated it didn't
he but to control the entry once more
he's having a much better session here
second time around remember this is the
guy who does confess that he has a bit
of a fear of heights which is a strange
complaint when you want to be a 10 metre
platform diver that that's a new high
mark for him into the nineties he didn't
manage that last night so he's come to
compete go see Greta from Cuba down in
10th position in with three and a half
somersault three point two so he can't
afford to get too much wrong here well
we got it all right
[Applause]
and again oh that's close isn't it you
take out his disastrous second dive in
the prelims without 21.6 that we
preferred to a couple of times
how much further up the rankings would
he have been give him another 50 points
he's good dives coming Gleb galperin
the 27 year old from Moscow double world
champion double Olympic bronze he's the
man remember who's had al injury worries
forward three and a half somersault
there just a 3.0 degree of difficulty
the girlfriend had some problems with
his second dive low tariffs here he's
gonna have to fight back with his last
three good scores but only a three
tariff so 72
you'll know what's coming next with
Peter Waterfield having a really
disappointing evening last night Tom
Daly is carrying British hopes entirely
on his young shoulders arm stand back
triple somersault 3.5 no towel for extra
grip for four Tom see how long he holds
the dive right at the top this was Tom's
top scoring dive in prelims than 89 very
impressive on the platform look so in
control good push just not quite 100%
vertical with the entry but the judges
are gonna like most of this crowd trying
to put a little bit of pressure on the
judges to maybe convince them that it
was slightly better than it was so he's
not 100% vertical and he's not 100%
square either but it's a very good dive
in every other aspect great line toes
pointed and fingers to toes and an 84
they're just a 5-point short of last
night's effort Victor mini vibe from
Russia reverse three and a half
somersault tucked experiencing any big
aims for the first time
very composed waiting and he's got his
mind completely right and clear the
visualization may be going on there
jump well away from the platform if that
didn't compromise the somersaults or his
entry position this dive too from that
standing position close to the platform
you you can't have a worry but took that
out of the equation and abide by taking
himself well away lots of clearance room
there compromise those if you jump out
rather than up you'll find yourself
short of time not that seventy nine
point two is very solid Columbia is
Victor Ortega who was taken diving when
he was just three years of age he's back
in 17th position so this arm stand back
triple somersault three point three
needs to come off for him
well it didn't really
larger splash didn't control the entry
so just modest scores coming in in the
sevens 3.3 the difficulty discuss that
to tattoo it it's about his love of life
happy in Spanish is at betta its life 69
3 that's life don't always get the
scores you want whoever said life is
supposed to be fair and told Sakharov
next he's just a bar for cat at 11th
this forward four and a half somersault
or nice very good at this four and a
half somersault the divers have
attempted that this is one of the better
efforts very tight tuck position and
eights across the board for zakharov not
much to complain about there not much to
deduct so they don't 88.8 chinese would
think that was a lucky dive with all
those aids it's the lucky number I think
they prefer one hundred and eight they
rule it out Riley McCormick from Canada
trains and studies in Arizona State
University in the states this is an
inward three and a half somersault and
he's just out of the picture in 14th at
the moment
Eric Sain went out to the competition
last night Canada will be disappointed
if they didn't have a finalist in its
ten meter competition McLaurys going to
have to find something in the second
half of this semi-final or that was
close to just the feet rolled over a
little just to leave less than a 100
percent impression for the judges maybe
one six going to be tight around that
cutoff point yanked the AG wheeler from
Cuba back through and a half somersault
a couple of Olympic Games two World
Championships he would regard a final
position as reward for the training and
the dedication
okay we only had trouble with this dive
last night sixty four point eight only
and the judges aren't going to be too
generous again I would suggest these
issues with the entry he was well short
almost disastrously so in terms of the
scores was fives and a five and a half
four fifty five point eight and that
will be tough to recover from the
defending champion Matthew Mitchum only
non Chinese diver to win a medal in
Beijing ruined the clean sweep in with
three and a half somersault now or
beautiful
is back to near his best
[Applause]
[Music]
three point two that's like it
he loves to smile for the camera doesn't
he that he loves this stage well he is a
showman and to be fair even during the
difficulties last night he came up
smiling and waving at the camera I think
he's one of those athletes Roger he just
finds it a joy to be here wow I'm at the
Olympics he's old he's done it all
before but he just thrives on it and in
86.4 for Matthew he picked up another
five points on his prelim effort for the
same dive if he's feeling enjoyment and
no pressure that makes him even more
dangerous if he can relax into he's
diving Nick McCrory now from the United
States 13th as a forward four and a half
somersault with a three point seven
tariff which he will have been looking
to cash in on he just sounded a little
heavy footed on the platform and not
quite sure he really had a vertical body
on the entry here the replay will show
us not that the judges see this but he
was just still working his way out of
the somersaults as he entered the water
and so still bend at the hips just held
him back a little on his marks because
of that
maybe three to five high tariffs so that
helps alexander bondar from ukraine 15th
arm stand back double somersault two and
a half twist this was his problem last
night 57.6 for this dive so keep your
fingers crossed for him
long hold
well it's better than last night but
there's still room there it's it's a
real worry when they stay up there that
long
the ankles were never together until
entry really and it wasn't quite
vertical but he's got away with one in
terms of improvement from last night leg
form was pretty ropey one of the great
things about the games is how you've
sensed that the crowd is supporting
every competitor obviously the the Brits
are getting a massive support but you do
feel in those long pauses the crowd of
willing them to do it well he's picked
up 25 points there bond on high tariffs
on that dive even though there were a
couple of faults even Garcia is carrying
on from where he left off last night at
least in wood for a half somersault four
point one this this is a big dive and
he's in third place after his opening
two dives in four and a half somersaults
from a standing start you've got to be
quick
he was pretty quick I was just looking
to see how much knee bender was going to
be as he launched off the platform not a
great deal really even still generated
good power and the feet just came apart
for that to finish that's such a shame
to get from the split tuck to get the
ankles together timing not easy and an
eighty six point one long hold at the
top you can feel that 15,000 odd people
just all holding their breath wondering
when he's going to make that decision to
launch we were a little bit critical of
that dive but he still picked up nine
points for the on the same one from last
night when I say we it was me wasn't it
thank you Kevin Sanchez from Mexico
second after the opening couple of Dimes
arm stand back triple somersault and
again the pool hushed
oh dear
entry wise that's a disaster at this
level and he will be punished the judges
do not like to see that even if you do a
lot right before then which he seemed to
do but the timing was wrong
came out too early over-rotated massive
splash and he's under five right across
well they'll get away with that in the
semi-final stage having had such an
impressive start but that's got to go if
he's there tonight
Martin Wolfram has been outstanding
reverse three-and-a-half somersault top
of the pile at the moment he may stay
there that was a good effort degree of
difficulty we'll just hold him back a
little a three point three he competed
here in February of that World Cup event
which gave many of the divers a chance
to sample the atmosphere and the water
he was ninth in the Timmy to platform
then but he is a bit of an unknown
quantity and maybe wanted to the others
will be wondering just how much this
guy's got in his locker seventy nine
point two for Martin she's lowest dive
so far Sascha Klein up next back a bit
after good work last night and the start
of today now he's got an arm stand back
triple somersault through three point
five the tariff he's in eighth place
well this was his top dive in the
prelims and maybe it will be again 90
2.75 last night for Sasha takes a lovely
Pike position he did get a couple of 9s
for it last night eight and a half's and
eight so not quite as good but
delightful to watch well-executed and an
eighty nine to five seems fairly happy
with the way the competition is going
wonderful same can be said for Lynn UA
who will have only the very highest
level of expectations he's fourth after
two rounds back three and a half
somersault boys now that again that was
the only 100 point died last night
even Chabot couldn't this one oh he's
just perfect through the air
[Music]
[Applause]
unbelievable and nine and a half's come
in and we're heading for three digits
here he got a 10 there that's going to
be taken out with three nine and a
half's and a 102 point six there it is
our first hundred point dive in the semi
there may well be a competition within
the competition between these two
Chinese teammates and rivals of course
Chabot now reversed three and a half
somersault and a disappointing second
dive which is really quite out of
character he's back that's not a 100
point dive because he doesn't have the
tariff but the form is there see how
much deeper into a squat he gets to
drive up off the platform
he has got a history of landing plenty
of tens 25 perfect tens in a in a series
back in 2011 a FINA diving World Series
event in Beijing 90 405 exactly the same
markers that I've yielded last night
now this would be interesting Lin ua has
taken over at the top of the leaderboard
David Boudia scum from 18th to 3rd the
Mexican of the Germans still holding
their own Tom Daley has worked his way
up the field as well Matthew Mitchum
just ahead of the cut Nick McCrory
Rowley McCormick are the ones under
pressure
Alexander Bondar hanging on in there
12 remember the cutoff to go through to
tonight's final the standard has gone up
a notch or two from last night I
undeniably rods there you see this
across competitions qualifying the top
boys just want to get there and they're
holding something back
not now David Boudia is transformed
overnight
he's now in third place reverse three
and a half somersault for his fourth
dive three point three the tariff well
he'll be relieved to have done a good
job with that
that was the dive that got him only 44
points last night eliminate that from
his total come up with something better
which he's certainly done here and he'll
continue to be knocking around the top
five
Matthew Mitchum made mention of this man
when he was talking about the
inconsistent performances across the
preliminary Sir David Byrd ah he doesn't
belong in 18th position and he won't be
there 85 Boyd eight things going much
better for the American cause agero he
too has improved significantly from the
preliminary competition he's up into
ninth place arm stand reverse triple
somersault for his fourth dive in his
sixth dive program three point four the
tariff well done excuse me he this was
his top scoring dive last night and he
might be able to do the same again
I wonder what the penalty would be for
dragging their towel into the pool with
you experience Thailand he was fifth in
Beijing half instan go sir well 25th
14th in Sydney oh he's not looking too
comfortable back problems plagued many
of these top athletes in the pool and at
the gymnastics and the sports are
closely related as I'm sure you're aware
Gleb galperin now from Russia oh that's
better much better he's been a little
inconsistent through his first three
he's the one who missed a couple of
years through injury I mean he's a
proven competitor and I think he's just
proved it well he needs to lift himself
up the standings in a 99.1 for galperin
his best dive so far his second dive was
a 37.4 so he's really got to rattle up
some big numbers with his closing two
dives as well as that one here comes the
heartthrob young Tom Daly I'm feeling
he's still gonna be young Tom Daley in
about 10 years time because everybody
just has that view of him in Britain
forward four and a half somersault
nicely done again gives the crowd plenty
the cheer
willing him on willing the judges not to
give him a good score as well just short
of the vertical but again he's one of
these divers as the top boys can just
minimizes the splash what whatever the
entry angle so will Mak to that GB
success has stunned many of the home
fans I can tell you and Tom Daley has to
turn that expectation into inspiration
as many other athletes have done and
found that the the crowd support has
really taken them the extra mile here at
point eight and again he's Daly's
improving across the board
Victor mini buy of his 10th
stand back double somersault two and a
half twist three point six and needing
to maintain those standards
a little untidy at the bottom I'm not
sure if he was waving to someone with
his toes or just looking for that
extension from fingers to toes but he's
over rotated there we go not sure what
that achieves except to give us
something to talk about Roger
maybe it's like maybe it's like a
trigger hmm quite all the performers and
even golfers talk about the trigger when
he's just going to decide when to when
to do it yeah make yourself move forward
press Victor Ortega from Colombia 17th
in with three and a half somersault he
really doesn't matter round up there
executed well
[Music]
feet just slightly apart on entry but
again from sidon it's one of those
little faults you can get away with
considering the judges position as they
study the dive 78 for picked up a few
marks on his preliminary effort many of
the divers he says that half his
training is actually out of the water
two or four hours a day spent in the gym
anton zakharov now reversed three and a
half somersault
he's down in 7th place I think he had a
better entry position than when the
splash indicated sometimes it works the
other way
[Music]
he is pretty much vertical but just
couldn't match that angle with the
splash he's done well 84 1 5 zakharov
moving along quite nicely scores in the
70s and 80s
Riley mcCormick his fourth divers an
armed stand back triple somersault we're
getting to the journals about on every
20 minutes which is 10 minutes less than
last night so getting a chance to get
into a little bit more of a rhythm once
he gets into that armstand position for
the back triple somersault very good
very good
so three point three the tariff sixty
nine point three for this one last night
not the tightest tuck position you'll
see like the entry angle
kicks it out from the platform very tidy
judges are proved with those eights
seventy nine point two that keeps him in
the hunt for a place in tonight's final
young Claire Aguilar from Cuba still has
work to do I'm staying back double
somersault one and a half twists three
point to another lower Terrace so
execution has to be exemplary if he's
going to make a run for the final twelve
good hold
wonderful entry not quite square for my
view but the position with the at least
as far as vertical as concerned was a 1
and was splashed not there at all so
good impression well one of those nines
is going to count because there was
three of them and that will help
and then eighty three point two is
picked up 13 points for that dive from
the prelims that's a bonus now the four
men who retained their 10-meter title
were Samuel Lee Robert Webster both
Americans the famous Klaus DiBiase from
Italy and Greg Louganis the most iconic
figure perhaps in diving Matthew Mitchum
pretty iconic himself in his own way
reverse three and half somersault oh
well he he must have slept well I think
he just faces it now he did impression
don't you he's happy to be here and a
happy competitor is often a good one boy
wait for this the judges really liked
what they saw from Mitchum here and with
good reason
near perfection this is the joy of
competition I would like to see that
from anyone and a 90 point seven five I
think the other divers have been looking
across and just thinking oh he might be
on a little bit of a bit of a ride
Nick McCrory that's rather more
pragmatic problems ahead of him
12 right on that cut line reverse three
and a half somersault for the American
well that's beautiful dive by dive we're
just seeing the standard improved I know
we're moving up to the higher seated
divers but they're not disappointing
that they're living up to their rankings
so or solid nines here McCrory well this
is what we should be seeing we want to
see the medals tonight decided on
excellence not on somebody making a
mistake or slipping out of it you know
you want to see the top divers really
pressed into something that dazzles and
gets this crowd right up on their feet
Alexandre bond up 14th place and
fighting to stay in the competition with
the back three and a half somersault got
it got all of it that's a great dive
from banda
[Applause]
Stacy's ambitions was being wanting to
become an Olympic champion and then
Sports Minister if that's okay
we were like ambition there's nothing
wrong with a sports minister being a
former athlete no no something about it
certain said Coe has gone into the more
political sphere and done all right with
these games so who knows in the future
no it's been an outstanding experience
for all of us and as an outsider you say
that there it's been an absolute
pleasure to be here and see a well run
games and totally enjoyable experience
well said even Garcia having a good
morning fourth I'm standing back double
somersault two and a half twists for the
synchro silver medalist
yes he just sort of lent into the
dispatch from the platform then pushed
off and the hesitation in the end led to
some indifferent execution sevens that
he would have liked more he's gonna be
okay he's come in as the sixth highest
and he's only had scores in the 80s
that'll get the job done but that one
wasn't his best an 81 his lower score so
far we second of the two Mexican divers
they're both from Guadalajara he's got a
german sanchez inward four-and-a-half
somersault four point one this is a big
one this is his toughest dive he nearly
got a hundred for it last night
well I can't see that getting around 98
high tariffs so if you were get most of
the value out of it then you're going to
get a very good score but the feet were
apart there and the splash not ideal and
the the judges didn't miss that little
form break or the splash of course it's
the most obvious indication of a problem
with the entry straight into the
analysis but an 86 instead of a 98 and a
12-point slip they're talking of let's
they Martine vault frame has just aged
back a bit after a really impressive
start again and you come up to this
level of competition back three and a
half somersault three point six still
sitting in fifth place
good effort Wolfram
he was one of those divers last night
who climbed up the rankings very
consistently after his second dive he
went from 19th the 10th to 8 to 6 to
fourth
so he really moved into the competition
with some momentum you might be tempted
to have him as a bit of an each-way
because quite sure just how much he can
pile on but he's he's done very well
96 for Sasha Klein more experienced
German diver 26 years of age serves in
the Army back three and a half
somersault biked 3.6 well very nice
again he's so consistent his dives last
night range from 81 to 92 left him the
third highest qualifier in that respect
he's like a Chinese divers that just
doesn't give you anything bad so he's
gonna be he's gonna be there abouts we
can just pull out a moment of
inspiration he might want fancy his
chances of getting on the podium this
evening Lin UA now leading the field
forward four and a half somersault 3.7
for the 21-year old remember is just
coming off a dive of 102
[Applause]
last night this one earned him 92 and
he's taking the challenge - chuubo the
Middle's aren't on the line yet but he
is making a statement I think I'm going
to be putting the pressure on
he is a long way up from that Wide Shut
thing three stories up if you like
perfect form as he enters the water
ninety four three five looks
disappointed with a 94 he hadn't himself
Linney's five four and eight stone five
cube oh five three and nine two complex
powerful figure now back three and a
half somersault and a lot of tubers
power evident there comes through those
strong thighs big knee bent here up and
away and that allows him to get through
those somersaults so quickly look for
the water and then say to the judges
what have you got for me well nine and a
half and a ten in there but the ten goes
out it's one of the top two he's back Oh
a hundred and two point six if you don't
mind and that's his first triple digit
score for the competition - Chinese
divers are definitely pushing each other
in this competition
Xu has been beaten by Lin this year
there's the leaderboard after round for
China one and two David Boudia still
doing well Sasha Klein and Martin
Wolfram and Tom Daley just working his
way up the field in seventh now here's
what really matters this morning Victor
mini buy of twelfth and Banda from
Ukraine
well he's point seven five behind him a
little bit more of a gap - Riley
McCormack but nothing between the
Russian and the Ukrainian not that
there's any rivalry
between those two camps anyway but only
0.6 between first and second so a real
battle at the top a real battle on the
bubble and a great little session
unfolding here and we're lucky to be
here Roger it's just the joy and those
watching who've got tickets for tonight
will feel even luckier still because
they know for the atmosphere the tension
is going to rise yet again and David
Boudia
has come out here the Smalling and made
sure he's in the frame to be a serious
contender
I don't want to say for the bronze medal
position but he is third after
back three and a half somersault there
little splashy on landing if I can put
it that way but David is diving much
more to his experience and reputation
here in the semi-final and in the
prelims
he's just folded that over a little to
create the bigger than desirable splash
he wasn't far from vertical and an
eighty two point eight runs in the
synchro where the great avala to the
synchro is you've only got one Chinese
opponent to beat as he were whereas here
with two individual competitors then it
makes it doubly difficult to get on that
podium Jose Guerra tenth wants to get
into that final tonight reverse three
and a half somersault three point three
well again he jumped well out from the
platform but in no way did that stop him
getting through the somersaults and he's
done an excellent job with the entry
minimal splash here even if he wasn't
quite at the vertical yes he was at a
bit of an angle judges liked it there's
79 to just a modest tariff there of 3.3
web galperin started off the preliminary
round so well very quickly into his
reverse three and a half somersault
straight off the board as soon as he was
called 17th after four dives this dive
only got in 34 point six five last night
was the one that nearly tipped him out
of the top 18 he's got so much to do to
get into the top 12 because he's he's
had one very bad dive of 37 he's second
make up some ground here with an 89
point one so he's potentially making a
late run into the 12 but lots to do
still well Greg Alfred had barely hit
the water before the raw started to
build up to an ounce Tom Daly onto the
platform Daly getting more into his
stride up into seventh back three and a
half somersault for the 2009 world
champion back three and a half
somersault then hiked
that's a great effort no no no how much
mental damage is done by doing a dive
badly but this one last night 39.6 but
he is now that no problems at all
where was the splash not there and
you're getting a very strong impression
that not only will he be in the final
he's a contender with at ninety one
point eight and that's now Tom's best
dive of the competition last night and
today
well boost his confidence no end victor
mini by of living on the edge down 12th
position now it's the back three and a
half somersault his fifth dive takes his
time
really chases time
we're like TallyMan above had a bit of
mental baggage to leave up on the
platform with that died that yielded you
less than fifty last night great push
off the platform beautiful straight legs
in the pike reaches for the water the
feet coming over just a tiny amount
pressure on as we get late into this
competition to force your way into that
1291 point eight huge well-timed
just when he needed the boost of the
points Victor Ortega back in eighteenth
and maybe just wanted to complete his
Olympic spirits with a couple of solid
dives back three and a half somersault
now well better if he's one of those
competitors Roger doesn't like to leave
himself hesitating up there too long for
the negative thoughts to enter he's
straight into his work this is one of
his better dives here in the semi hasn't
been his session solid eights though
had more success as a synchro diver six
in the Beijing Olympic Games
Anton zakharov ninth place fifth dive
arm stand back triple somersault all the
twenty six-year-old well we didn't hold
it for too long up there and maybe not
for long enough that's a poor dive for
zakharov a shocking angle coming in to
the water and hence the big splash too
late
kicking it out he was almost at 45
degrees and a 3675
that will hurt could have cost him a
place in the final that one mistake
that's what it's all about it's the the
pressure knowing that you cannot afford
to blow one dive and succeed Riley
McCormick close to the top pole 14th
reverse three-and-a-half somersault
might just see this as a chance to cash
in after a Sakharov disappointment very
good so when you're eliminating from 18
down to 12 and you're on the bubble you
start to look around so Who am I going
to beat here McCormick might have
slipped ahead of a couple with this it's
an excellent dive
it's the real competition here this
morning is down of in this sort of 9th
to 15th because they're the ones are
under the most pressure 79 went to there
for McCormick better result than last
night which was a 64 for that dive
this is young Claire Aguilar from Cuba
looking to reach the final for the first
time 16th place might just be a stretch
too far for him reverse three and a half
somersault a Yank --let stormed home
last night in the prelims going from
19th place to 12th to 10th these last
few dives this one
not such a good result just coming in at
that less than ideal angle so all in the
timing of kicking out from the last
somersault
now mr. Mitchum what have you got for us
this time I'm staring back triple
somersault three point three the tariff
stand seems an awful long way up for all
the most powerfully built divers in
world diving really expect the
unexpected from Matthew pretty good
I think he's safely through
this was only a 66 dive for him in the
prelims
not his perfect line on entry that we
saw from his previous dive
he's just edging closer grimace this
time he knows he left a bit out there
had a severe abdominal muscle tear which
cost him a place in last year's World
Championship so he's ground to make up
Nick McCrory in 11th place looks a
lonely figure up at the top of that 10
meter ball just over 39 feet
you know money back three and a half
somersault now for Nick McCrory from the
states very good seventy nine point two
for the dive last night brings a smile
to the US coaching staff great height
off the platform so he's already threw
his first somersault before he passes it
on the way down give yourself time to
get the entry angle just right which he
did started off as a swimmer and said
that to switch to diving because he
looked more fun having a bit more fun
with those scores I mean it's just
watching that line in the pool hour
after hour lap after lap how much fun is
that why don't you jump off ten meters
Alexander Banda with a reverse three and
a half somersault thirteenth he's still
full of hope here
well well that's one of the best entries
of the night the dive got in 89.1 last
night
he's a little sort of vibration of the
hips and legs here as he straightened
out for the entry too quick for the
judges to worry about that though and on
89.1 and bond or he's going well I just
cashed in there his countryman Sakharov
I think you had the disappointing dive
now we're getting back up more towards
the top end with even Garcia from
Mexico's sixth place after four dives
now a reverse three and a half
somersault tucked qualified sixth
sitting sixth at the moment
almost had too much time he's so quick
with his somersaults so he's just
overcooked it at the end well let's go
one and a half done by the time it goes
past the platform and spotted the water
so early he pushed himself past the
vertical but as he comes out of the
split tuck ankles together there's lots
to like about that dive seventy four to
five the difficulty was three three just
a reminder that all these divers not had
not only had to qualify from last night
but just to be in London now they did
well in last year's World Championships
or were continental champions or through
the diving World Cup this year which
carries on around the world
chairman Sanchez reversed three and a
half somersault with work to do again
well that's a very good dive
[Applause]
he's entitled to like this one up and
away
not too close to the platform to give us
any palpitations slight twist of this
angle of entry here vertical if not
square the judges didn't seem to mind
three 9s there and an eighty nine point
one again that's the kind of error Roger
what we we need a couple of angles to
pick that up on right back on track
after that Martin Wolfram from Germany
and twenty-year-old from Dresden back
two and a half somersault two and a half
twist fifth after four dives
yeah it looked like it was going to be
untidy at entry that fits into me all
over the place but he's again controlled
the splash very well good push off the
platform through this complicated dive
finds the water hmm
good but he's got better remember at the
World Championships last year he didn't
even get through qualifying finished
20th so he's really trained on here
86 for Sascha Klein completing the
encouraging position for Germany was a
reverse three and a half somersault for
his fifth dive was ranked fourth and he
received an eighty nine point one for
this dive last night but that was
scoring nines so you won't get that this
time with a three point three tariff
this grimacing through those tight
rotations
seventy four to five so 15 points
slipped there at the top of the board
having a good competition for number one
ranking tonight with Kubo this is linen
at you a will that I understand back
double somersault two and a half twist
well that's his biggest splash of the
night
well the morning at least sorry and that
that dive that got him ninety one point
eight in the prelims won't be doing so
again he got off on the wrong angle
there when arms was stronger in the
push-off than the other never had it
online and he's dominated the syncro
seen over the last few years the
reigning Olympic champions ten metre
synchro World Championships in 2007 and
nine but to bow has hugged the
individual limelight now if he gets this
it's a 100-point dive it's his toughest
Tara three point seven forward
four-and-a-half somersault tucked
now quiet he's short on the entry so
he's just showing the rest of the field
that he can make mistakes very high
tariffs dive though so he's got to score
well mistake about that but the hips
still bent at entry and it doesn't
matter that it's chuubo the judges have
to be totally objective which they have
been here they've seen that mistake
ninety four thirty five is still a good
score but five less than for the same
guy last night it's a bit like competing
against some of the Kenyans on the track
you've got to believe that you can win
it and not just take it for granted
they're still top of the pile to Beau
and Lynn you a David butai but look Tom
Daley up into fourth that's what's
getting the crowd cheering here Thomas
Martin wolfram and Sasha Klein from
Germany still holding their own Matthew
Mitchum the right side of the line Jose
Guerra and the man really under pressure
is Riley McCormick no German sanchez has
seen his program fall away dramatically
and really rather surprisingly yes that
the Mexican competitors qualified fifth
and sixth but it could be only one of
them will make it through on those
positions and we have to keep an eye on
Matthew Mitchell's last dive too I was
riding him into the final two early he's
under some pressure inside the 12 at the
moment but only just
sixth and final series have died these
divers have been competing now for about
an hour and 37 minutes to get through
five dives organizers have got the
competition moving along as swiftly as
possible and now it's the American from
Abilene Texas the 23 year old and the
bronze synchro medallist third after
five rounds back two and a half
somersault two and a half twists in
there as well and that man is safe
stumbled into the semi-final in last
position but he's going to be much
higher up the rankings where we're
expecting to see him and in contention
tonight you have to say when he's diving
now according to his reputation and his
results very strong man great core
strength five foot nine one of the
taller divers on show here and then
ninety three point six very consistent
session his head that's his highest dive
good finish you like that because a
guerra 12th back two and a half
somersault two and a half twists diving
for a place in the final tonight
might just have done it too
[Applause]
three point six the tariff through the
twists
into the water at a good angle low
splash it's given the judges something
to admire a coach looks a little
concerned but he's the 33 year old
remember the real standard bearer for
diving in Cuba and the oldest diver in
the competition declared galperin and 27
year old from Moscow trying to put all
those injury problems of the past behind
him back two and a half somersault to an
half twist my well be his farewell show
back down in 16th
alprin would love to take back his
second dive which got less than 40
points an eighty four point six and he
needs a few things to go right for him
to make the 12 next up its the local
hero it's Tom Daley who has been getting
better and better and will be desperate
to produce a strong dive to finish his
program and send him into tonight's
final with the confidence that he surely
craves for fourth after five dives
reverse three and a half somersault with
a comparatively modest three point three
degree of difficulty there we are
he's through hardly a splash at all rips
through the three and a half somersaults
he's the man most of the crowd have come
to see and they are giving him a major
send-off into tonight's final are the
judges though that's the all-important
thing all the applause air cooing around
this Aquatic Center and an eighty nine
point one count him in is another man
confirming his position in the platform
final very smiley young man apart from
when the competition is on so he will
have a little bit more to relax about
after this morning Victor Mille by
seventh back 2 & a half somersault two
and a half twist which you want to make
sure that he just gets through tidally
that's good he's in as well
a long way to fall from seventh to
thirteen and he could even lift himself
a place this was very good there's the
water
I'm going in straight and he certainly
does
whole different level of competition so
far this morning we're getting far more
of those ain't the haves and nines bit
more like it
and the Russian support crew very happy
with it that's his higher score of the
semi ninety three point six so he's in
Victor Ortega from Colombia right down
in seventeen film just wanting to walk
away from the Olympic Games with a good
dive behind him which he does reverse
three and a half somersault were three
point three wonder if that's his last
dive in Olympic competition he's 24 he's
got his sights set on being a lawyer
second Olympic Games it's not a bad
effort overall in his sporting career as
it to Olympic Games but from Colombia
down to Brazil it's not that far is it
he might just be tempted to go one more
cycle
I wonder it'll be his decision of course
seventy nine point two well done
training so demanding though trying to
carry two careers and compete at the
very highest level that's tough and torn
zakharov now in 15th place he collapsed
in his program a little bit back two and
a half somersault two and a half twists
well he's a little bit of a chance here
with a 3.6 tariff on this one this is
going to be very tight pressure on
around the cut and as the eight and a
half's come in for zakharov and judge is
thrown in a nine and a half year
I'm sure where that comes from oh no I'm
bigger pardon he'll have an anxious
fifteen twenty minutes
Riley McCormick from Canada 13th diving
to give Canada a representative in the
concluding event in the pool tonight
back three and a half somersault I need
pressure on this dive one outside the
top 12 or spectacularly good high
tariffs with this one was his best dive
last night he obviously likes this one
he saves his best till last Canada have
picked up two bronze in these Olympic
Games in the diving and they they'll
want to be here competing tonight John
not just as spectators boy he might have
done it big sprinkling of nines across
the scoreboard for him only applaud the
work of his opponent here ninety seven
point two well that's one of the top
dives of the night talk about digging
deep when it's necessary hi Claire oak
wheeler is bringing out the ball of the
table at the moments back two and a half
somersault two and a half twist to end
his Olympic campaign
better finish from him disappointing
considering he came in as the tenth
qualifier
didn't make the final in Beijing and
again it's a semi final ranking for him
top 18 in the world
[Music]
now there's a lot of pressure on this
dive for Matthew Mitchum who's coming in
to his last dive ranked 11th but those
around him are really finding extra
points with the last dive the Olympic
champion wants the chance to defend that
title tonight and cannot afford anything
less than his best now it's his highest
taraf dive back to a half somersault two
and a half twist oh I don't know I don't
know some concern faces amongst those
interested in his outcome this was a big
splash looked to be struggling and I
think we've just lost him these scores
aren't enough and that will be a loss to
tonight's final he was still one of the
big names being mentioned in the metal
frame coming into this competition and
it will be a real shock and a real story
if Matthew Mitchum has missed that cut
and he is flirting with it on those
marks Steve
well that's 70.2 is his lowest scoring
dive of the night and had the highest
tariff so I should say morning again the
man who produced of the end dive to end
all endives four years ago is suffering
the opposite now nick McCrory's got his
own worries he's tenth back two and a
half somersault two and a half twists
needs a steady points return
I think that was steady enough push off
the platform one of the taller divers
here 511 it's a lot of body to get
around and up into the air but he does
it very efficiently and he should be
okay in fact he will be look at the
number of competitors left and where he
sits
McCrory's in alexander bond our ninth
after five dives back two and a half
somersault two and a half twist looking
over his shoulder
very nice entry bond or
well there is the disappointment of
Matthew Mitchum I think he knows he's
gone tearful into his campaign that leg
form here bond are not so special and
seventy nine point two one of his lower
rank dies for the session but he's okay
he's qualified
on our little scoreboard here up in our
commentary position as its confirmed who
can't be displaced a little Q is coming
up next to their name but Mitchum knows
it's there's no final for him even
Garcia H finishing with a four with two
and a half somersault with three twists
with a three point eight tariff didn't
finish it as he would have liked it came
down pretty quickly as he looked to get
into the twisting section of his dive
and over the leaks come
what you doing those
and a seventy nine point eight so he's
in it's been a strange session note for
this man
German Sanchez who was looking very
impressive at one stage but he's fallen
away he's packed down in 14th forward
four and a half somersault three point
seven needs a big haul from that twenty
year old from Guadalajara silver
medalist in the synchro with event
Garcia does not want to be split from
his countryman for tonight
this was his lowest scoring dive in the
prelims and I think he's making amends
here II only got sixes for it last night
but today some eights and a good tariff
of three seven and an eighty eight point
eight
he's waiting hmm
Martin Wolfram in fifth place forward
four and a half somersault to end three
point seven a tariff very nice a little
short on the entry not much
and a big tariff
he's have a good competition so far
though responding to the challenge of
this the very highest level of
competition which is pretty new to him
who dire daily wolfram Mina by of
mccrory Guerra Garcia Navarro bondar
McCormick they're all in
Sascha Klein in sixth place we're also
looking to be joining the party and
should do my selling disastrous happens
to his back two and a half somersault
two and a half twists he's been
consistent
well no disaster there but not quite
what he would like to show us in the
final but he'll be there
the judge is very much of a same view
about this dive which gotta make t1 in
the prelims and again
nothing if not consistent
now the battle within the battle Lin you
a from China second behind his
countrymen back two and a half
somersault two and a half twists to
conclude an impressive program
well impressive again Lin you a there
was a little bit of a leg form break at
the top of the dive but he got it all
back together very neatly just there the
ankles drifted apart but restores his
usual immaculate position as he enters
the water
so will it be China one too going into
the final these scores don't carry
forward of course Roger may well carry
forward in one or two divers mines as
they say the standards that the Chinese
divers have set not that it comes as any
surprise at all and leading the field
has been nineteen-year-old
cubo the bookies favourite back two and
a half somersault two and a half twist
well why not end the session with
something near perfection to boat could
give us another 100 point dive here such
power off the platform and through the
rotations diver of the Year for the
governing body FINA last year and
another tantalizing display from him
gonna be great tonight
well very close to the hundred ninety
seven point two he's the top man he is
the one to beat they are the ones to be
the two Chinese divers Tom Daly getting
a massive cheer as he leaves the pool
fourth place Matthew Mitchum though he
will be devastated he has just missed
out by one spot Matthew Mitch and no
opportunity to defend his Olympic title
so there's one that the rest of the
field does not have to worry about and
he could have been a threat but he
didn't make it
David Buddha's come out of this from
18th up to third
Martin Wolfram just behind Tom Daley
their mini buy of a quarry sasha klein
germany doing well for sake we're up
making the cuts even Garcia Aleksandr
Banda Rowley McCormick scrambling aboard
the big headline to miss out Matthew
Mitchell and German Sanchez as well who
was so promising before also misses the
boat glib galperin to will be
disappointed as will those six who don't
go forward but Matthew Mitchum
the negative headline story if you like
from tonight and I'll save you any
accusations and buyers to say that from
an impartial point of view the
competition will be a little bit the
less for the for the lack of someone
like him so he can't really have any
complaints Roger he missed that that
12th position by some 13 points we know
he's come here less than in the
condition he was four years ago not able
to throw the difficulty into some dives
but he didn't finish well he had the
opportunity to confirm his place wasn't
able to make the most of that last dive
that had the highest tariffs and so paid
the price here and we can have he can
have no complaints he knew what his
limitations were coming here and as much
as we like watching him dive I think if
he'd made the twelve in the form that
we've seen from him he wasn't going to
threaten for the Middle's his
personality though is something that
adds to the whole sense of occasion here
mind you this competition so far
today has really cranked up the
anticipation and Tom Daley's progress
will certainly crank up the volume
there'll be 17,000 in here tonight it is
one of the top tickets in town if you
were lucky enough to get it and really
the the level of competition has risen
here because it was it was fierce
especially for that last place on board
and we've got an idea of what is to come
tonight it's gonna be a great
competition the crowd will lift the roof
off for Tom Daley
there'll be generous applause and real
excitement about what the two top
Chinese competitors have for a to bow
and linear and whaddaya coming from last
qualifying position to third maybe he's
got more to offer as well but so much to
look forward to Roger so can anyone
produce the performances to challenge
these Chinese divers who
I have shown their nerve and their skill
their impassive on the outside and they
just let their their diving do the
talking after you Mitchum
ways farewell though to this Olympic
final were pakia tonight at 7 o'clock
it'll be great platform final the last
event here in this diving pool make sure
you don't miss it